Finding Aid for Carl Eugen Guthe Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Philippine Expediton Photographs
  - Philippine expedition, 1922-1925
    - Album 3
      - The overhang after digging c-11, [3-87] (Box 3)
      - The upper entrance to c-11, [3-88] (Box 3)
      - The Cross on the hilltop - c-11, [3-89] (Box 3)
      - The beginning of a boroto - Bohol, [3-90] (Box 3)
      - The boroto farther along, [3-91] (Box 3)
      - Boroto with the sides on, [3-92] (Box 3)
      - Boroto detail, [3-93] (Box 3)
      - Splitting hemp leaves - Bohol, [3-94] (Box 3)
      - Rotting hemp on the shore, [3-95] (Box 3)
      - Beating hemp, [3-96] (Box 3)
      - Drying hemp fibre, [3-97] (Box 3)
      - Hemp bundled for market, [3-98] (Box 3)
      - Soaking coco shells for salt, [3-99] (Box 3)
      - AWD under sail, DAW's picture, [3-100] (Box 3)
    - Album 4
      - S.E. coast of Peñow de Coron, [4-1] (Box 3)
      - Close up of cliff - S.E. coast of Peñow de Coron, [4-2] (Box 3)
      - Picturesque shore Peñow de Coron, [4-3] (Box 3)
      - Native hut in cliff shadow - S.E. Coron, [4-4] (Box 3)
      - Recent cave burial - S.E. Coron, [4-5] (Box 3)
      - Native huts along the coast - Coron Isl., [4-6] (Box 3)
      - Togbauna, fishing village, [4-7] (Box 3)
      - General view - Burial cliff - Banuangdan, Coron (2), [4-8] (Box 3)
      - Close up of no. 8, [4-9] (Box 3)
      - The burial fissure - close up of no. 9 (c-64), [4-10] (Box 3)
      - Location of N.W. cave (c-65), [4-11] (Box 3)
      - Interior of c-65, [4-12] (Box 3)
      - N.W. coast of Peñow de Coron, [4-13] (Box 3)
      - N.W. coast of Peñow de Coron, [4-14] (Box 3)
      - Detail - west coast - Peñow de Coron, [4-15] (Box 3)
      - Detail - west coast - Peñow de Coron, [4-16] (Box 3)
      - Doorway of large cave W. coast - Peñow, [4-17] (Box 3)
      - Interior of large cave W. coast - Peñow, [4-18] (Box 3)
      - Marche's cave - Peñow de Coron, [4-19] (Box 3)
      - The 'dobe house - Palancals place, Busuanga Isl., [4-20] (Box 3)
      - Mt. Capoan, Malampaya Sd. - Palawan (2), [4-21] (Box 3)
      - A mountain stream, Malampaya Sd. - Palawan (2), [4-22] (Box 3)
      - A swimming pool, Malampaya Sd. - Palawan, [4-23] (Box 3)
      - A large dugout canoe - Malampaya, [4-24] (Box 3)
      - "Comaso" - white pigeon - Malampaya, [4-25] (Box 3)
      - Wallacis family - Malampaya, [4-26] (Box 3)
      - Sheer cliff - Palawan, [4-27] (Box 3)
      - Street scene - Bacuit - Palawan, [4-28] (Box 3)
      - Cave of refuge - Bacuit - Palawan, [4-29] (Box 3)
      - Interior of refuge cave - Bacuit - Palawan, [4-30] (Box 3)
      - One of the floor supports - refuge cave, [4-31] (Box 3)
      - Deep undercut - Bacuit, [4-32] (Box 3)
      - Undercut cliffs. Bacuit Bay, Palawan, [4-33] (Box 3)
      - Inabuyatan Island. Bacuit Bay, Palawan, [4-34] (Box 3)
      - Native loom. Bacuit Bay, Palawan, [4-35] (Box 3)
      - Salt drain. Bacuit Bay, Palawan, [4-36] (Box 3)
      - General location (c-67), [4-37] (Box 3)
      - Close-up (c-67), [4-38] (Box 3)
      - Puisail Island, Bacuit Bay, [4-39] (Box 3)
      - Coffin (c-69), [4-40] (Box 3)
      - Leper on raft - Culion Leper Colony, [4-41] (Box 3)
      - General view - Culion Leper Colony, [4-42] (Box 3)
      - General view - Culion Leper Colony, [4-43] (Box 3)
      - Over the hilltop - Culion Leper Colony, [4-44] (Box 3)
      - Administration building - Culion Leper Colony, [4-45] (Box 3)
      - Steps and theatre - Culion Leper Colony, [4-46] (Box 3)
      - Worcester plaza and dormitories - Culion Leper Colony, [4-47] (Box 3)
      - Public convenience - Culion Leper Colony, [4-48] (Box 3)
      - The old church door - Culion Leper Colony, [4-49] (Box 3)
      - The old church watch tower - Culion Leper Colony, [4-50] (Box 3)
      - Maida - manoc, Sulnan, [4-51] (Box 3)
      - Wading towards Maida, - manoc, Sulnan, [4-52] (Box 3)
      - Truck used in Siguijor, [4-53] (Box 3)
      - Picturesque road, San Juan, Siguijor, [4-54] (Box 3)
      - Bauca unloading on beach, San Juan, Siguijor, [4-55] (Box 3)
      - Present day cemetery, San Juan, Siguijor, [4-56] (Box 3)
      - Hills of Barrio Lamancapan, Siguijor, [4-57] (Box 3)
      - Closer view of same hills as no. 57, [4-58] (Box 3)
      - Burial pit in Lamancapan hills, [4-59] (Box 3)
      - Site of the green vase in Lamancapan hills, [4-60] (Box 3)
      - Sherd cache on Bungtud can Clgustin Siguijor, [4-61] (Box 3)
      - Crocodile killed at Santa Maria (2), [4-62] (Box 3)
      - Subano house, Siocon Bay, Zambo, [4-63] (Box 3)
      - Large Subano house, Siocon Bay, Zambo, [4-64] (Box 3)
      - Francisco Mateo on house steps of no. 64, [4-65] (Box 3)
      - Carved Xylophone - Subano-moro house, [4-66] (Box 3)
      - First steps in making boroto - Siocon Bay, [4-67] (Box 3)
      - Diving girls, Zansbranga. harbor (2), [4-68] (Box 3)
      - Bandstand, Pershing Plaza, Zambo, [4-69] (Box 3)
      - One side of Pershing Plaza, Zambo, [4-70] (Box 3)
      - Regal Monument, [4-71] (Box 3)
      - Buhelebung, Basilan, [4-72] (Box 3)
      - Flag stones from hills, Buhelebung, Bas., [4-73] (Box 3)
      - Olive celadon, Buhelebung, Bas., [4-74] (Box 3)
      - Beach, Kaubungan Isl., Basilan, [4-75] (Box 3)
      - Two gold bracelets, Kaubungan, [4-76] (Box 3)
      - CEG being carried ashore, Kaubungan, [4-77] (Box 3)
      - Specimens for sale, Kaubungan, [4-78] (Box 3)
      - Old graves, Tonguil Island Salu, [4-79] (Box 3)
      - Old grave stone, Salu, [4-80] (Box 3)
      - Moro vintass near Jolo, [4-81] (Box 3)
      - C & G.S. Survey boat "Fathonior" - Jolo, [4-82] (Box 3)
      - Waterfront, Jolo, [4-83] (Box 3)
      - Chinese quarters on pier, Jolo, [4-84] (Box 3)
      - Jolo market, [4-85] (Box 3)
      - Modern jar, Sultan Harroun's house, [4-86] (Box 3)
      - Ancient Chinese grave - distance, [4-87] (Box 3)
      - Ancient Chinese grave - inscriptions, [4-88] (Box 3)
      - Ancient Chinese grave - with group, [4-89] (Box 3)
      - Hadji Baginda's grave - Bund Dato - distant, [4-90] (Box 3)
      - Hadji Baginda's grave - Bund Dato - close, [4-91] (Box 3)
      - Hadji Baginda's grave - Bund Dato - detail, [4-92] (Box 3)
      - Jolo from Bund Dato, [4-93] (Box 3)
      - Typical Moro hill house, [4-94] (Box 3)
      - Grave of sultan Hassim, [4-95] (Box 3)
      - Flags at cave Mouth. Buhnan Isl., [4-96] (Box 3)
      - Fred Worcester's aladin (2), [4-97] (Box 3)
      - Water gypsies - mouth of Siay R., Sibugay gulf, [4-98] (Box 3)
      - Tree trunks, Siay R., Sibugay gulf, [4-99] (Box 3)
      - Swamp views, Siay R., Sibugay gulf (2), [4-100] (Box 3)
    - Album 5
      - Interior of Cave 17, [5-1] (Box 3)
      - Overhang cliff - Cave 18, [5-2] (Box 3)
      - Vessel in situ - G62, [5-3] (Box 3)
      - Hillside location of G62, [5-4] (Box 3)
      - Calubian and bay from G62, [5-5] (Box 3)
      - View of boat from hilltop - Calubian, [5-6] (Box 3)
      - Path in jungle - Calubian, Leyte, [5-7] (Box 3)
      - Path in hemp patch - Calubian, Leyte, [5-8] (Box 3)
      - Two compañeros and stream - Calubian, Leyte, [5-9] (Box 3)
      - "Anne Day" anchored at Aocan Isl., [5-10] (Box 3)
      - Kellogg having tea on poop deck, [5-11] (Box 3)
      - Launch returning from Catbologan, [5-12] (Box 3)
      - General view - Lapundan, Daram, [5-13] (Box 3)
      - Guide and family and Motak - Lapundan, [5-14] (Box 3)
      - A vista at Lapundan, [5-15] (Box 3)
      - Fish trap net - drying - Talarora, Samar, [5-16] (Box 3)
      - Group of natives - Bagakay, Sam, [5-17] (Box 3)
      - Native house - Avcan Isl., [5-18] (Box 3)
      - Kellogg - drying hemp, near Calubian, [5-19] (Box 3)
      - Chicken on board, [5-20] (Box 3)
      - Magellan's monument - Mactan, [5-21] (Box 3)
      - Magellan's monument - Mactan, [5-22] (Box 3)
      - Magellan's monument - Mactan, [5-23] (Box 3)
      - Site of B-5 - Cebu, [5-24] (Box 3)
      - Juan Abella - crossing stream, [5-25] (Box 3)
      - Vessels in situ - B-6 - Cebu, [5-26] (Box 3)
      - Vessels in situ - B-6 - Cebu (2), [5-27] (Box 3)
      - Site of grave - B-6, [5-28] (Box 3)
      - The carriage for "Anne W. Day" - drydock, [5-29] (Box 3)
      - The carriage for "Anne W. Day" - drydock, [5-30] (Box 3)
      - Placing the "AWD" on the carriage, [5-31] (Box 3)
      - Scraping hull, [5-32] (Box 3)
      - Barnacles before scraping, [5-33] (Box 3)
      - AWD in drydock - from distance, [5-34] (Box 3)
      - AWD in drydock - side, [5-35] (Box 3)
      - AWD in drydock - stern, [5-36] (Box 3)
      - AWD in drydock - prow, [5-37] (Box 3)
      - Lifting an anchor at drydock, [5-38] (Box 3)
      - The carriage for AWD - at drydock, [5-39] (Box 3)
      - The carriage for AWD - at drydock, [5-40] (Box 3)
      - The carriage for AWD - at drydock, [5-41] (Box 3)
      - AWD coming into carriage, [5-42] (Box 3)
      - AWD high and dry, [5-43] (Box 3)
      - AWD high and dry, [5-44] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - Beginning of work, [5-45] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - end of work, [5-46] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - general view, [5-47] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - type of workmen, [5-48] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - skel. 1, [5-49] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - skel. 2, [5-50] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - skel. 6 before, [5-51] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - skel. 6 after, [5-52] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - native digging with crowbar, [5-53] (Box 3)
      - Naga, Cebu - the hills to the north, [5-54] (Box 3)
      - C-13 - Camotis (?) - before sieving, [5-55] (Box 3)
      - C-13 - Camotis (?) - during work, [5-56] (Box 3)
      - A native sailboat on Leyte coast, [5-57] (Box 3)
      - AWD tacking off Bilivan, [5-58] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Egid Samar - before cleaning, [5-59] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - half an hour later, [5-60] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - beginning on ridge, [5-61] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - after ridge was removed, [5-62] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - Morning of second day, [5-63] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - the southwest trench, [5-64] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - the grooved stone in situ, [5-65] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - three ungrooved stones as found, [5-66] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Skel. 1 (full length), [5-67] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Skel. 2 (incomplete), [5-68] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Skel. 3 (Jar), [5-69] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Skel. 5 (Jar), [5-70] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Skel. 9 (Jar), [5-71] (Box 3)
      - B-10 Boys drinking out of bamboo, [5-72] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - Kellogg sieving on beach, [5-73] (Box 3)
      - B-10 - Kellogg carried to launch, [5-74] (Box 3)
      - Wright, Samar - street scene, [5-75] (Box 3)
      - Vista on road to Shanger, [5-76] (Box 3)
      - Tigbao - tall grass - on road to Shangar, [5-77] (Box 3)
      - Native farm dress - Wright, Samar, [5-78] (Box 3)
      - Natives and store - near Wright, [5-79] (Box 3)
      - The barrio of Tutubegan near Wright, [5-80] (Box 3)
      - Carabou. just out of mudhole, [5-81] (Box 3)
      - Group showing native sunhat, [5-82] (Box 3)
      - House on Shanger's burial ground, [5-83] (Box 3)
      - General view Shanger's burial ground, [5-84] (Box 3)
      - Edge of Shangerts burial ground, [5-85] (Box 3)
      - River from Sanger's burial ground, [5-86] (Box 3)
      - C-16 - Cabungaan, Samar, [5-87] (Box 3)
      - C-16 - bringing out the sherds, [5-88] (Box 3)
      - Tacloban from the boat, [5-89] (Box 3)
      - Tacloban water front with AWD, [5-90] (Box 3)
      - Tacloban carraboa. and cart, [5-91] (Box 3)
      - Coco palms - at Turabanan, Samar, [5-92] (Box 3)
      - Shore line at Turabanan, Samar, [5-93] (Box 3)
      - Undercut cliff - Turabanan, Samar, [5-94] (Box 3)
      - Entrance to a cave - Turabanan, Samar, [5-95] (Box 3)
      - Interior of same cave - Turabanan, Samar, [5-96] (Box 3)
      - K-2 - Tinabanaan, Samar, [5-97] (Box 3)
      - 1917 cave burial - Tinabanaan, [5-98] (Box 3)
      - Modern coffins - Tinabanaan, [5-99] (Box 3)
      - Modern coffins - Tinabanaan, [5-100] (Box 3)
    - Album 6
      - Kellogg & large tecljaos - Tinabanaan, Samar, [6-1] (Box 3)
      - Fishing village - Tinabanaan, Samar, [6-2] (Box 3)
      - The natural bridge - Tinabanaan, Samar, [6-3] (Box 3)
      - Upper Celadon Cave - C-21 - Tinabaan, Samar, [6-4] (Box 3)
      - Lower Celadon Cave - C-21 - Tinabaan, Samar, [6-5] (Box 3)
      - Washing sherds on poop deck - Tinabaan, Samar, [6-6] (Box 3)
      - The new "skysail", [6-7] (Box 3)
      - Maidam river - C-23 - Subian, [6-8] (Box 3)
      - The "Atlas" - Dapitan harbor, [6-9] (Box 3)
      - Street scene - Dapitan (2), [6-10] (Box 3)
      - Parochial school, Dapitan, [6-11] (Box 3)
      - Plaza from hill, Dapitan, [6-12] (Box 3)
      - Native house, Dapitan, [6-13] (Box 3)
      - Steps in Spanish Fort - Dapitan, [6-14] (Box 3)
      - Powder chamber - Dapitan, [6-15] (Box 3)
      - Juan and red pitcher - Dapitan, [6-16] (Box 3)
      - In the swamp - Dapitan, [6-17] (Box 3)
      - In the swamp - Dapitan, [6-18] (Box 3)
      - In the swamp - Dapitan, [6-19] (Box 3)
      - The rock of Maria Oray - Dapitan, [6-20] (Box 3)
      - The swamp from the rock - Dapitan, [6-21] (Box 3)
      - The gang at the rock - Dapitan, [6-22] (Box 3)
      - Cave in hills - Tagolo Pt. - Dapitan, [6-23] (Box 3)
      - Coin cave - Tagolo Pt. - Dapitan, [6-24] (Box 3)
      - The coast - Tagolo Pt. - Dapitan, [6-25] (Box 3)
      - The coast - Tagolo Pt. - Dapitan, [6-26] (Box 3)
      - A fish trap - Dapitan, [6-27] (Box 3)
      - The coast near Dapitan, [6-28] (Box 3)
      - Hills around Marevelagos Bay, [6-29] (Box 3)
      - Silla Pt. from inland, [6-30] (Box 3)
      - Looking inland from near Silla, Pt., [6-31] (Box 3)
      - The rock shelter trail - Silla, Pt., [6-32] (Box 3)
      - The rock shelter trail - Silla. Pt., [6-33] (Box 3)
      - Point Silla from the sea, [6-34] (Box 3)
      - In the hills of Davao, Cebu, [6-35] (Box 3)
      - View of Mahiko - Bukidaon, [6-36] (Box 3)
      - Chinese jars interior of Bukidaon, [6-37] (Box 3)
      - Chinese jars interior of Bukidaon, [6-38] (Box 3)
      - Chinese jars interior of Bukidaon, [6-39] (Box 3)
      - 2 jars in Cagayan, Misamis, [6-40] (Box 3)
      - 2 jars in Cagayan, Misamis, [6-41] (Box 3)
      - Sea coast cave Larcua - Siguijor, [6-42] (Box 3)
      - B-16 - Larcua Siguijor, [6-43] (Box 3)
      - B-16 - Larcua SigiLijor, [6-44] (Box 3)
      - Waterfall near B-16 - Larcua - Siguijor, [6-45] (Box 3)
      - The gang at B-16 - Larcua - Siguijor, [6-46] (Box 3)
      - Landscape at B-21 - Larcua - Siguijor, [6-47] (Box 3)
      - A possible burial ground - Larcua - Siguijor, [6-48] (Box 3)
      - Hills of the interior near Larcua - Siguijor, [6-49] (Box 3)
      - Rice terrace walls Larcua - Larcua - Siguijor, [6-50] (Box 3)
      - Landscape - interior of Siguijor, [6-51] (Box 3)
      - Harvesting rice - interior of Siguijor, [6-52] (Box 3)
      - Rice paddies - interior of Siguijor, [6-53] (Box 3)
      - Jar in interior Siguijor (2), [6-54] (Box 3)
      - Rotting magney - Bauban, Siguijor, [6-55] (Box 3)
      - Farming land - B-24 - Siguijor, [6-56] (Box 3)
      - Farming land - B-24 - Siguijor, [6-57] (Box 3)
      - Farming land - B-24 - Siguijor, [6-58] (Box 3)
      - Church at Siguijor, [6-59] (Box 3)
      - Digging in B-20 - Siguijor, [6-60] (Box 3)
      - Small barrio church - Siguijor, [6-61] (Box 3)
      - Albino - San Juan - Siguijor, [6-62] (Box 3)
      - Big Spring - San Juan - Siguijor, [6-63] (Box 3)
      - Bridge at Big Spring - San Juan - Siguijor, [6-64] (Box 3)
      - Landscape near Maria - Siguijor, [6-65] (Box 3)
      - Church at Lazi - Siguijor, [6-66] (Box 3)
      - Convent at Lazi, Signijor, [6-67] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) Truck at Lagaspi, Albay, [6-68] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) MacDonald's house, Albay, [6-69] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) Cave picture - Albay, [6-70] (Box 3)
      - Mt. Mayou, Albay, [6-71] (Box 3)
      - Abandoned Colorado Mine - Masbati, [6-72] (Box 3)
      - Distant view - Schwabi Mine - Masbati, [6-73] (Box 3)
      - Distant view - Schwabi Mine - M-2 - Masbati, [6-74] (Box 3)
      - The works Schwab's Mine M-2 Masbati, [6-75] (Box 3)
      - The mill Schwab's Mine M-2 Masbati, [6-76] (Box 3)
      - The bucking board - M-2 Masbati (2), [6-77] (Box 3)
      - Alla sherd in situ - M-2 Masbati, [6-78] (Box 3)
      - Earth chute - M-2 - Masbati, [6-79] (Box 3)
      - Face of cut - M-2 -Masbati, [6-80] (Box 3)
      - Batungaan Valley - Masbati, [6-81] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) The wall of Batungaan Valley Masbat1, [6-82] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) Batungaan Rock - Masbati, [6-83] (Box 3)
      - Large cave in Batungaan Rock - Masbati, [6-84] (Box 3)
      - Skull cave in Batungaan Rock - Masbati, [6-85] (Box 3)
      - Coffin in Skull cave - Masbati, [6-86] (Box 3)
      - Another cave - Batungaan Rock - Masbati, [6-87] (Box 3)
      - The Mataba jar - Masbati, [6-88] (Box 3)
      - Cave 48 - Masbati, [6-89] (Box 3)
      - Cave 47 - Masbati, [6-90] (Box 3)
      - Monkey trap - Masbati, [6-91] (Box 3)
      - Digging in B-29 - Masbati, [6-92] (Box 3)
      - The jar of B-29 - Masbati, [6-93] (Box 3)
      - Lighthouse on Tanginque, [6-94] (Box 3)
      - Tanginque island and AWD, [6-95] (Box 3)
      - On Calachuchi R. Masbati - with Tailing, [6-96] (Box 3)
      - The swollen river near Heath's ranch, [6-97] (Box 3)
      - The old Lead mine on Heath's ranch, [6-98] (Box 3)
      - The old Lead mine (shaft) on Heath's ranch, [6-99] (Box 3)
      - Charles Tarling on horseback (2), [6-100] (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1939-1943
  The Correspondence series, 1939-1943 (0.5 linear feet), contains Guthe's incoming and outgoing professional correspondence from his final years at the University of Michigan. It has been arranged in general alphabetical folders by correspondent, with individual folders for a few of Guthe's regular correspondents, such as James B. Griffin and Eli Lilly. Most of the correspondence relates to Guthe's work as director of the Museum of Anthropology and University Museums.
  - A-F, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Gilmore, Melvin R. (Box 3)
    (includes correspondence with family members re: disposition of Gilmore's library and papers)
  - Greenman, Emerson F. (Box 3)
  - Griffin, James B. (Box 3)
  - G-J, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Kinietz, Vernon (Box 3)
  - K (Box 3)
  - Lilly, Eli (Box 3)
  - L (Box 3)
  - MacLean, Arthur (Box 3)
  - Matson, Fred (Box 3)
  - M, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Neumann, Georg (Box 3)
  - N-Z, 13 folders (Box 3)
- Journals, 1912-1944
  Journals, 1912-1944, (2 linear feet) comprises the journals kept by Guthe and his wife during several of his expeditions. All of the journals were damaged in a house fire in the 1950s. Notes from Guthe that were with the journals indicate that a typed transcript of the journals was created in 1970, but the fate of those transcripts is unknown. An ardent writer, Guthe's journals richly detail the day-to-day experiences, frustrations, and successes of expeditions. Journals from the 1920s are particularly strong. Later journals detail daily life, but not as extensively as the expedition journals.
  - Journal, 1911 (Box 4)
  - Carl Guthe, 1912-1916 (Box 4)
  - Carl Guthe, Central America / Paten Trip, 1920
    - Pages 1-272, "original copy" (Box 4)
    - Pages 1-272, carbon copies (Box 4)
    - Pages 1-152 (Box 4)
      (first two notebooks)
    - Second notebook through page 152, carbon copies; extremely damaged/fragile (Box 4)
    - Journal pg. 153-252, 1920 (Box 4)
    - Journal pg 253-272, 1920 (Box 4)
    - Journal Badly Damaged, 1921 (Box 4)
    - Journal, 1922-1926 (Box 4)
    - Journal, 1930 (Box 4)
    - Journal, June-December 1931 (Box 4)
    - Journal Badly Damaged, 1933 (Box 4)
    - Journal, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Journal, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Journal, 1944 (Box 4)
    - Pages 153-252 (Box 4)
    - Pages 253-272 (Box 4)
  - Grace Guthe, New Mexico-Colorado Trips, 1917 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Loose Pages and Notes, 1922-1931 (Box 5)
  - Trip 1 Western Samar with Mr. Worcester, November 6-12, 1922 (Box 5)
  - Trip 2 November 26-December 14, 1922 Western Samar; Trip 3, February 9-March 7, 1923 South West Samar, Suluan (First Contact), 1922-1923 (Box 5)
  - Trip 4 April 4-15, 1923 North West Mindanao; Trip 5, April 28-May 17, 1923 Dipitau, Mindanao, and Siquijor (Box 5)
  - Trip 6 June 19-July 17, 1923 to Albay and Lamarines Sur in Luzon; Trip 7, July 24-August 11, 1923 Masbate and Gold Wine (Box 5)
  - Trip 8 August 28-September 9, 1923 Iloilo and Masbate; Trip 9, September 25-October 4, 1923 Si Quiso-Walking Trip with Brown (Box 5)
  - Trip 10 Bohol, Suriago, Suluan, and the Typhoon, October 23-November 19, 1923 (Box 5)
  - Trip 11 December 4-21, 1923 to Manilla; Trip 12, January 19-26, 1924 Siquijor; Trip 13, February 2-22, 1924 Bohol, lived "Native" in Barrio near Loay, 1923-1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 14 to Calmianes group and Palawan with Mr. Worchester and son Fred, March 3-29, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 15 Suluan Cave, Completed, April 4-19, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 16 May 8-July 7, 1924 All the way around Mindanao; the Davad Hike, June 10-21, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 17 Bohol, August 17-25, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 18 Masbate, Roniblon, Tablas, and Mindoro, October 1-17, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Trip 19 to Zamboanga by "Common Carrier", January 19-February 3, 1925 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1921-1974
  Correspondence, 1921-1974, (0.5 linear feet) comprises two types of files. The first group appears to be a partial alphabetical file of Guthe's correspondence from 1925 to 1938, comprising only the letters A through C. Files of the second type do not bear any apparent relationship to the alphabetical files or any existing correspondence series, and their provenance is unknown. Additional correspondence can be found in the 1944 accession correspondence series.
  - General, A-C, 1925-1940; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - James B. Griffin, 1944-1952 (Box 5)
  - A. T. Hill, 1938 (Box 5)
  - A. V. Kidder
    - 1932-1934 (Box 5)
  - 1955-1963 (Box 5)
  - Frederick R. Matson, 1951-1974 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous un-filed, 1927-1943 (Box 5)
  - S. G. Morley, 1921-1922 (Box 5)
  - National Park Service, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Philippines, 1922-1925 (Box 5)
  - Vacation correspondence with office, 1935 (Box 5)
- Writings, 1905-1971
  Writings, 1905-1971, (1.0 linear foot) includes manuscripts, notes and publications written by Guthe. The earliest piece details 12 year-old Guthe's experience at President Roosevelt's 1905 inauguration. Early poems are included in the series. Some of the poems are about Guthe's wife, Grace. Professional speeches and publications highlight Guthe's detailed descriptions of his expedition experiences.
  - "The Inauguration Parade and Fireworks,", 1905 (Box 6)
  - Poems by Carl E. Guthe, 1909-1912 (Box 6)
  - Travel Lecture, 1920 (Box 6)
  - "Afloat and Afoot in Davao," Original manuscript with additional notes from Journal, 1924; 1966 (Box 6)
  - Unfinished Manuscripts written in Philippines (Box 6)
  - "'Evolution' of Man,", 1926 (Box 6)
  - "The Gold Encrusted Teeth of Samar,", 1926 (Box 6)
  - "Report on Philipse Castle and Sunnyside,", 1952 (Box 6)
  - Museums Study, Notes and Research Materials, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Notes for talk in Columbia, S.C., 1971 (Box 6)
  - "Anthropologists do not want to be coordinated," notes, undated (Box 6)
  - "The City of the Last Stone,", undated (Box 6)
  - "Hunting Ruined Cities in Guatemala,", undated (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Documents (Box 6)
  - American Association of Museum Reports of the Research Associate, 1953-1959 (Box 6)
  - Museum News, selected issues, 1938-1954 (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts, 1955-1963 (Box 6)
  - Publications reprints, 1931-1967; 4 folders (Box 6)
- Clippings, 1916-1965